<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS on Polymath.cloud</title>
    <link>https://polymath.cloud/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AWS on Polymath.cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 23:46:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://polymath.cloud/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Management Fundamentals for AWS</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/aws-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 23:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/aws-management/</guid>
      <description>AWS Config One of the largest headaches we have is understanding:
 What resources do we have? Do we have resources that are no longer needed? Their status, security vulns. How are they linked? What changes have occurred on a resource? Is the infrastructure compliant with governance controls? Accurate auditing information?  AWS Config records and captures source changes allowing us to perform actions against the data. It can:
 Capture resource changes Act as a resource inventory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Cost Management and Customer Support</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/aws-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/aws-cost/</guid>
      <description>There are 4 main support plans::
 Access online resources (basic) General guidance from AWS (Developer) 24-hour technical support (Business) Dedicated Account Managers and Personaliiseid Consultation  Total Cost of Ownership The Total Cost of Ownership (ToC) calculator is a free calculator to compare AWS cloud and on-premise costs. It&amp;rsquo;s designed for anyone who is considering migrating to AWS.
It creates a report after we complete a short questionaire.
The report will include estimated on-premise costs such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of AWS Authentication, Authorisation, and Access Control</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/aws-authentication-authorisation-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/aws-authentication-authorisation-access/</guid>
      <description>Authentication Comprised of 2 parts of information.
 Who you are?  Presenting your identity (login username). Unique value within the system we are trying to authenticate to.
Verify you are who you say you are. Passwords, MFA, etc. This does not have to be unique.  We may use credit card pin numbers for authentication. Identity = credit card, verify = pin number.
Authorisation Happens before authentication.
System in which we have authenticated to establishes what level of privileges we can access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating your own VPN with PiHole &amp; UnBound on AWS</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/pihole-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 23:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/pihole-vpn/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this blog post we will:
 Create our own VPN on AWS Add PiHole to iit Use Unbound as our DNS resolver Access the VPN using Wireguard Not go bankrupt doing it!  Step 1 Create an AWS lightsail instance on Amazon.
We use Lightsail instead of EC2 because EC costs £0.12 / GB on outbound transfers. That means for 1 TB / month it&amp;rsquo;ll cost £120.
Lightsail costs £3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to IAM with AWS</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/aws-iam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 23:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/aws-iam/</guid>
      <description>Identity &amp;amp; Access Management Identities are required to authenticate to AWS accounts.
Username = identity Password = verification
Access management relates to what an identity can access once its been authenticated.
The AWS IAM service is used to centrally manage and control security permissions.
 Users: These are objects within IAM identifying different users. Groups: These are objects that contain multiple users. Roles: These are objects that different identities can adopt to assume a new set of permissions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disaster Recovery with AWS for CCP</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/aws-disaster-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/aws-disaster-recovery/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll need to invoke our disaster recovery plans to restore our data if our storage or server fails.
With traditional backup methods, the data we need might not be available because:
 Backup data is stored in the same location as the production data, and the disaster impacted the backups. If using a tape backup method, the tapes could fail making the data unreadable. The tapes could get lost when in transit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>