<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AZ-900 on Polymath.cloud</title>
    <link>https://polymath.cloud/tags/az-900/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AZ-900 on Polymath.cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:42:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://polymath.cloud/tags/az-900/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of Azure Services</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/azure-overview-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/azure-overview-services/</guid>
      <description>Compute  Azure Virtual Machines Azure App Service Azure Container Instance Azure Functions   Storage  Blob Storage Azure File Storage Azure Data Lake Storage Gen2 Relational Databases Azure Synapse Analytics NoSQL   Netowkring  Virtual Network (VNet) Subnets VVNet peering Azure VPN ExpressRoute   Miigration  Azure Migrates Azure Active Directory   DevOps  Azure DevOps Azure Pipelines Azure DevTest Labs Azure CDN   IoT  Azure IoT Central Azure IoT Hub Azure Sphere   Analytics  Azure HDInsight Azure Databricks Azure Synapse Analytics   AI  Cognitive Services Azure Bot Service Azure Machine Learning Studio Machine Learning Services   Integration  Logic Apps Event Grid    Compute Azure Virtual Machines Runs VMs for Windows &amp;amp; Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://polymath.cloud/azure-overview-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://polymath.cloud/azure-overview-storage/</guid>
      <description>Blob storage Binary Large Object (Blob) storage is a way of storing large files.
There are 3 types of Blobs in Azure:
Blob Blocks Divided into blocks of up to 100MB in size. Blobs of up to 4.75TB can be stored as blob blocks in Azure.
Using multiple blocks to represent the blob allows for more efficient handling of large blobs. Usually, the complexity of managing individual blocks is handled for you so you can simply deal with the entire blob rather than individual blocks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>